Finding Aid for the Howard Morehead photographs and papers PASC-M.0142
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1. Photographs, circa 1940-2002
  - Subseries 1. People, 1947-2002
    - Uggams, Leslie, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
      168 negatives. Includes: Sidney Poitier, Brock Peters, Si Zentner and His Orchestra.
    - Upchurch, Phil, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
      3 prints.
    - Washington, Dinah [with unidentified trumpet player], undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
      22 negatives.
    - Weldon, Ann, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - White, Slappy, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
      4 negatives. Outside the Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Building, 1999 W. Adams Blvd.
    - Whitfield, Mal, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
      16 negatives. At Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum.
    - Wiggins, Gerald, undated-1999 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      25 prints; 1 transparency; approximately 550 negatives. The early negatives possibly include Andy Simpkins (bass) and Paul Humphrey (drums).
    - Williams, Joe, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
      8 prints; 1 negative; proof sheet.
    - Joe Williams - matted prints, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Williams, Tony [of The Platters] and unidentified woman, circa 1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      7 negatives.
    - Wills, Maury with Lionel Hampton and others, circa 1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Wilson, Gerald, undated and 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      4 prints; approximately 70 negatives.
    - Wilson, Gerald - oversize print, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Wilson, Nancy, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Witherspoon, Jimmy, undated and 1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      72 negatives; 1 print; 1 proof sheet; obituary.
    - Jimmy Witherspoon - oversize matted print, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Yorty, Sam, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
      1 matted print inscribed by Yorty.
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
      41 prints; 40 proof sheets.
    - Unidentified - large format, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
      1 prints; 4 matted prints; 3 proof sheets.
    - Unidentified - oversize, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Unsorted negatives, undated (Box 7, Box 11, Box 12, Box 19, Box 21)
      Mostly glamour photography, including cheesecake photos and nudes.
    - Unsorted transparencies, undated (Box 19)
      Mostly glamour photography.
  - Subseries 2. Events and organizations, 1958-2000
    This subseries contains photographs of jazz festivals, beauty pageants, performances, businesses, and locations.
    - Academy Awards for 1957, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Carver House [Las Vegas Interracial Hotel], circa 1962 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Nichelle Nichols and John Bubbles are in performance and on the marquee.
    - Cavalcade of Jazz, 1955 July 24 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      48 negatives; proof sheets. At Wrigley Field, Los Angeles.
    - Central Avenue Jazz Festival, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      10 prints; approximately 432 negatives; proof sheets; program.
    - City of Angels Jazz Festival, 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      2 prints; 36 negatives; proof sheets; flyers.
    - Club Checkerboard [television series], circa 1959 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Approximately 125 negatives.
    - Dodgers Stadium, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Game between the Dodgers and Oakland A's, with Reggie Jackson batting. Proof sheet.
    - Double M Jazz Salon, 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      12 prints; approximately 300 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Drum City, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Ebony Fashion Fair, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      65 negatives.
    - Golden State Mutual Life Insurance, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Includes photos of buildings and staff; advertising art; calendar images. Approximately 1000 negatives.
    - Holman United Methodist Church, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
      62 negatives.
    - Jazz a la Carte, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
      36 negatives; proof sheet.
    - Jazz at Drew, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      1 print; 9 transparencies; approximately 500 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Jazz at Drew, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Approximately 468 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Jazz at School, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      72 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Jazz Bakery, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Jazz Goes to Church, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      5 prints; 62 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Jimmy Cleveland Benefit, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Lena Horne Cosmetics, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Long Beach Jazz Festival, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Los Angeles City Hall, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
      10 negatives.
    - Miss America, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
      33 negatives.
    - Miss Black America, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
      120 negatives.
    - Miss Bronze California, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Approximately 420 negatives; 15 transparencies.
    - Miss Universe, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - MOCA Jazz, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      11 prints; approximately 180 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Musicians union benefit, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
      69 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Pacific Jazz Festival, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
      108 negatives.
    - Playboy Jazz Festival, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      2 prints; approximately 500 negatives; proof sheets.
    - Playboy Jazz Festival, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Approximately 180 negatives; proof sheets.
    - The Shriners [giving an award to Sammy Davis, Jr.], circa 1960 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Transport a Child Foundation [with Duke Ellington, Tony Bennett, Steve Allen, Greg Morris, Tom Bradley], 1967 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      4 prints; 4 proof sheets.
    - Tribute to Billie Holiday, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
      Approximately 65 negatives; proof sheets..
  - Subseries 3. Howard Morehead, circa 1940-2000
    Contains photographs of Howard Morehead alone and with others; duplicates have not been noted.
    - Black Journalists Association of Southern California, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Morehead is receiving an award; Dick Gregory is in attendance. 9 prints; 6 small prints; proof sheet.
    - Morehead, Howard, circa 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      13 prints; 1 matted print. Includes Carrolle Drake and Gordon Currie.
    - Morehead, Howard - matted photomontage, circa 1950 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Morehead, Howard, circa 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      6 prints.
    - Morehead, Howard, circa 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      41 prints; 2 proof sheets. Includes Bruce Davis of the Manson Family.
    - Morehead, Howard, circa 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      5 matted prints.
    - Morehead, Howard - matted prints, circa 1970-1979 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      8 large format prints.
    - Morehead, Howard, circa 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      50 prints; 3 proof sheets.
    - Morehead, Howard, circa 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      19 prints; 11 small prints; 1 proof sheet fragment; 24 negatives.
    - Morehead, Howard - oversize matted print, circa 1990 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Morehead, Howard with Brook Benton and Louie Robinson, circa 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Morehead, Howard with Ray Charles, circa 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Morehead, Howard with Cindy Crawford, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
      3 prints; handwritten note from Crawford.
    - Morehead, Howard with Dorothy Dandridge and Otto Preminger, circa 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Morehead, Howard with Sammy Davis, Jr., 1958 and circa 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      3 prints [2 on the set of Gone with the West].
    - Morehead, Howard with Rosey Grier, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      1 print [on the set of The Thing with Two Heads].
    - Morehead, Howard with Loyal Griggs, circa 1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      1 print [on the set of The Ten Commandments].
    - Morehead, Howard with Jayne Mansfield, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Morehead, Howard with Sidney Poitier, circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Morehead, Howard with Nancy Wilson, circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified personal and family photos, circa 1940s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 18)
      40 snapshots.
  - Subseries 4. Digital images, 1997-2000
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    SERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this series will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    - All Stars of Jazz screen saver, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      2 3.5" floppy disks.
      Restrictions on Access
      Use of electronic/digital format material requires special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing.
    - Kodak picture CD, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Compact disc.
- Series 2. Business and personal papers, 1958-2001
  Includes correspondence and other documents regarding Morehead's various business ventures and his employment at KABC. Files including the word "incident" contain material regarding disciplinary measures taken against Morehead at the television station, which cumulatively resulted in him filing a racial-discrimination lawsuit.
  - Backstreet Artist Gallery, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Biographies and press releases, circa 2000 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Black photographers, circa 1994 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Book queries, 1995-2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bronze Beauty, 1987-1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Includes model questionnaires and resumes; press releases.
  - Calendars, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - California State University, Northridge, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence regarding the donation of Morehead's papers.
  - Cards and post cards, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Includes Black Is More Than Beautiful beefcake cards.
  - City of Angels Jazz Festival program, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1992-2001 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - CRM Public Relations, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Cuban prisoner return incident, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Cultural Affairs Department, 1990-1997 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Double M Jazz Salon fliers, 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Edwards, Teddy, 1990-1994 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Includes article about Edwards by Morehead.
  - Equipment lists, 1963-1977 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Eye on Music, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Contains mock-up of proposed book of photography.
  - Fyffe, Bill, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - General correspondence, 1979-2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Head shots, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Includes Jesse James Hollywood.
  - Inside Edition incident, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Jazz at Drew programs, 1995-1999 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - KABC documents, 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - KABC employment, 1976-1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - KABC lawsuit, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - KABC memos, 1974-1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - KABC retirement, 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Late return/illness incident, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Lena Horne: The Lady and Her Music program, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Los Angeles Dodgers incident, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Michael Ray Gammon incident, 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Miss Bronze California program, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - MOCA programs, 1995-1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Monterey Jazz Festival programs, 1963-1968 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Periodicals, 1964-1991 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Elegant, 1:6, 2:3 [with feature on Eartha Kitt photographed by Morehead], 2:6, 2:8; Players, 17:11.
  - Personal papers, 1992-2003 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Photocopies, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Playboy, 1958-1993 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Includes letters from Playboy explaining that they do not consider "foreign, Oriental and Negro girls" as models.
  - Playboy Jazz Festival programs, 1983 and 1999 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Ray Charles Song Folio, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Writings by Howard Morehead, undated and 1997 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Series 3. Video cassettes, 1980-2001
  Mostly home recordings; VHS tapes unless otherwise noted.
  RESTRICTED ACCESS: Use of moving image material requires production of viewing copies.
  - Aretha [Franklin], 1986 (Box 13)
  - Aretha Franklin / Lou Rawls, undated (Box 13)
  - Artist Extraordinary - Bill Pajaud, undated (Box 13)
  - Big Band Bash / American Pop Singers, undated (Box 13)
  - Billy Childs at Jazz Salon, 2000 (Box 13)
  - From Jump Street / Ray Charles 20/20 / Dizzy Gillespie "Mayport jazz", undated (Box 14)
  - The Gerald Wiggins Trio with the Southeast Symphony Orchestra, 2001 (Box 14)
  - H. Morehead Interview, undated (Box 14)
  - Interview of Photographer Howard Morehead by Tom Reed on KSCI-TV, 1990 (Box 14)
    2 copies, one VHS, one Beta.
  - Jazz at the Smithsonian with Art Blakey, Wynton and Branford Marsalis / Sarah Vaughan and Wynton Marsalis with the Boston Pops Orchestra, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - Monty Alexander Trio at Union Station, undated (Box 15)
  - Nancy Wilson at O.C. Smith Memorial, undated (Box 15)
  - Ray Charles with the Boston Pops / Jazz at the Snowbird: Dave Brubeck / Spoleto '81, undated (Box 15)
  - Saoul Mamby vs. Esteban De Jesus / Larry Holmes vs. Scott LeDoux / Miss Universe / Oscar Peterson and Boston Pops / Bill Evans, 1980 (Box 15)
  - World of Photography, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Photographs of Howard Morehead, 1990 (Box 16)
    U-matic tape.
  - World of Photography (Master), undated (Box 16)
- Series 4. Sound recordings, 1963-1998
  RESTRICTED ACCESS: Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Ray Charles - I'm All Yours Baby!, undated (Box 17)
    12" vinyl record.
  - Ray Charles - Ingredients in a Recipe for Soul, 1963 (Box 17)
  - Ray Charles - Just Between Us, 1988 (Box 17)
  - Ray Charles - The Complete Country & Western Recordings, 1959-1986, 1998 (Box 17)
    CD box set.
    Disc 4 of this CD set is missing, but there are two copies of the liner notes booklet.
  - Blues Women, undated (Box 17)
    CD-R.
  - Teddy Edwards, Eric Burrell, undated (Box 17)
- Series 5. Scrapbooks, 1944-1958
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1944-1947 (Box 19)
    Includes material regarding Howard Morehead's military service.
  - Scrapbook, 1952-1958 (Box 19)
    Contains clippings and covers from publications targeting African-American readers, including the Los Angeles Sentinel, Ebony, Tan, Jet, Sepia, and Hue; application to join the American Society of Magazine Photographers.
- Series 6. Books, 1962-2000
  - The Black Music History of Los Angeles - Its Roots by Tom Reed [Los Angeles: Black Accent Press], 1992 and 2000 (Box 25)
    2 copies inscribed by the author.
  - The Brown Derby Cookbook by Leonard Louis Levinson [Garden City: Dolphin Books], 1962 (Box 25)
  - An Illustrated Bio-Bibliography of Black Photographers, 1940-1988 [New York: Garland Publishing], 1989 (Box 25)
  - Monterey Jazz Festival: Forty Legendary Years by William Minor [Santa Monica: Angel City Press], 1997 (Box 25)
  - The Nigger Bible by Robert H. DeCoy [Blawhit] [inscribed by the author], 1967 (Box 25)
  - The Nigger Bible by Robert H. DeCoy, with a preface by Dick Gregory [Los Angeles: Holloway House] [inscribed by the author], 1967 (Box 25)
  - The Spook Who Sat by the Door by Sam Greenlee [New York: Bantam Books] [inscribed by the author], 1972 (Box 25)
  - Claxonography by William Claxton [Kiel: Nieswand Verlag] [inscribed by the author], 1995
    Separated Material
    Item removed to stacks because of size.